<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><metadata><idinfo><citation><citeinfo><origin>Petersen, Mark D.</origin><origin>Mueller, Charles S.</origin><origin>Moschetti, Morgan P.</origin><origin>Hoover, Susan M.</origin><origin>Rukstales, Kenneth S.</origin><origin>McNamara, Daniel E.</origin><origin>Williams, Robert A.</origin><origin>Shumway, Allison M.</origin><origin>Powers, Peter M.</origin><origin>Earle, Paul S.</origin><origin>Llenos, Andrea L.</origin><origin>Michael, Andrew J.</origin><origin>Rubinstein, Justin L.</origin><origin>Norbeck, Jack H.</origin><origin>Cochran, Elizabeth S.</origin><pubdate>20180301</pubdate><title>Chance of potentially minor-damage ground shaking in 2018 based on the average of horizontal spectral response acceleration for 1.0-second period and peak ground acceleration for the Western United States</title><geoform>shapefile</geoform><othercit>Digital geospatial data and supporting metadata can be downloaded from:
https://doi.org/10.5066/F7Cf9PC4</othercit><onlink>https://doi.org/10.5066/F7Cf9PC4</onlink><lworkcit><citeinfo><origin>Petersen, Mark D.</origin><origin>Mueller, Charles S.</origin><origin>Moschetti, Morgan P.</origin><origin>Hoover, Susan M.</origin><origin>Rukstales, Kenneth S.</origin><origin>McNamara, Daniel E.</origin><origin>Williams, Robert A.</origin><origin>Shumway, Allison M.</origin><origin>Powers, Peter M.</origin><origin>Earle, Paul S.</origin><origin>Llenos, Andrea L.</origin><origin>Michael, Andrew J.</origin><origin>Rubinstein, Justin L.</origin><origin>Norbeck, Jack H.</origin><origin>Cochran, Elizabeth S.</origin><pubdate>20180301</pubdate><title>2018 One-Year Seismic Hazard Forecast for the Central and Eastern United States from Induced and Natural Earthquakes</title><geoform>map</geoform><serinfo><sername>Seismological Research Letters</sername><issue>Volume 89, Number 3.</issue></serinfo><pubinfo><pubplace>Albany, CA</pubplace><publish>Seismological Society of America</publish></pubinfo><onlink>https://doi.org/10.1785/0220180005</onlink></citeinfo></lworkcit></citeinfo></citation><descript><abstract>A one-year seismic hazard forecast for the Central and Eastern United States, based on induced and natural  earthquakes, has been produced by the U.S. Geological Survey.  The model assumes that earthquake rates calculated from several different time windows will remain relatively stationary and can be used to forecast earthquake hazard and damage intensity for the year 2018. This assessment is the first step in developing an operational earthquake forecast for the CEUS, and the analysis could be revised with updated seismicity and model parameters. Consensus input models consider alternative earthquake catalog durations, smoothing parameters, maximum magnitudes, and ground motion estimates, and represent uncertainties in earthquake occurrence and diversity of opinion in the science community.  Near some areas of active induced earthquakes, hazard is higher than in the 2014 USGS National Seismic Hazard Model (NSHM) by more than a factor of 3; the 2014 NSHM did not consider induced earthquakes. In some areas, previously observed induced earthquakes have stopped, so the seismic hazard reverts back to the 2014 NSHM.
This data sets represents the results of calculations of hazard curves for a grid of points with a spacing of 0.05 degrees in latitude and longitude. They represent the chance of experiencing potentially damaging ground shaking for fixed ground shaking levels that corresponds with MMI = VI. The values are obtained by averaging the probability of experiencing MMI = VI based on a peak ground acceleration value of 0.1155 g for site class D, and the probability of experiencing MMI = VI based on 1.0-second spectral acceleration value of 0.102 g for site class D.  The data are for the Western United States and are based on the long-term 2014 National Seismic Hazard Model.</abstract><purpose>This map is intended to provide a more robust estimate for the chance of experiencing potentially minor-damage ground shaking from an earthquake by averaging the probabilities obtained from peak ground acceleration hazard curves and hazard curves for 1.0-second spectral response acceleration.</purpose></descript><timeperd><timeinfo><rngdates><begdate>20180101</begdate><enddate>20181231</enddate></rngdates></timeinfo><current>publication date</current></timeperd><status><progress>Complete</progress><update>None planned</update></status><spdom><bounding><westbc>-125.0</westbc><eastbc>-100.3</eastbc><northbc>49.2</northbc><southbc>28.0</southbc></bounding></spdom><keywords><theme><themekt>none</themekt><themekey>Seismic</themekey><themekey>Earthquake</themekey><themekey>Hazard</themekey><themekey>Induced</themekey><themekey>Natural</themekey></theme><place><placekt>http://geonames.usgs.gov/</placekt><placekey>Arizona</placekey><placekey>California</placekey><placekey>Colorado</placekey><placekey>Idaho</placekey><placekey>Montana</placekey><placekey>Nevada</placekey><placekey>New Mexico</placekey><placekey>Oregon</placekey><placekey>Texas</placekey><placekey>Utah</placekey><placekey>Washington</placekey><placekey>Wyoming</placekey><placekey>USA</placekey><placekey>United States</placekey></place><temporal><tempkt>none</tempkt><tempkey>2018</tempkey></temporal></keywords><accconst>None</accconst><useconst>The data are not to be used for areas outside the conterminous United States.   Acknowledgment of  the U.S. Geological Survey, National Seismic Hazard Mapping Project would be appreciated in products derived from these data.</useconst><ptcontac><cntinfo><cntperp><cntper>Ken Rukstales</cntper><cntorg>U.S. Geological Survey - Geologic Hazards Science Center</cntorg></cntperp><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing address</addrtype><address>Box 25046, MS 966</address><city>Denver</city><state>CO</state><postal>80225</postal><country>USA</country></cntaddr><cntvoice>303-273-8677</cntvoice><cntemail>rukstales@usgs.gov</cntemail></cntinfo></ptcontac><native>Microsoft Windows 7
Esri ArcGIS 10.3</native></idinfo><dataqual><attracc><attraccr>This data set is based on a seismological model.  The following report provides information on quality assessment for the data set:
Petersen, M.D., Mueller, C.S., Moschetti, M.P., Hoover, S.M., Rukstales, K.S., McNamara, D.E., Williams, R.A., Shumway, A.M., Powers, P.M., Earle, P.S., Llenos, A.L., Michael, A.J., Rubinstein, J.L., Norbeck, J.H., and Cochran, E.S., 2018, 2018 One-Year Seismic Hazard Forecast for the Central and Eastern United States from Induced and Natural Earthquakes: Seismological Research Letters, Volume 89, Number 3.</attraccr></attracc><logic>Polygon topology is present.  Data were checked for gaps, slivers and polygon closure using topology tools in ArcGIS and visually.</logic><complete>Data are complete.  No features were generalized.  All features are attributed.</complete><posacc><horizpa><horizpar>The location of features is based on calculations of a seismological model for the study area.  The location of each point is considered to be correct within the confines of computer accuracy.</horizpar></horizpa></posacc><lineage><procstep><procdesc>Based upon the long-term 2014 National Seismic Hazard Model, a suite of hazard curves were calculated for an equally spaced grid of points covering the conterminous United States.  The grid has a cell spacing of 0.05 degrees in both latitude and longitude.   Using log-log interpolation, the hazard curves at each grid point were used to determine the probability of experiencing MMI = VI based on a peak ground acceleration value of 0.1155 g for site class D, and the probability of experiencing MMI = VI based on 1.0-second spectral acceleration value of 0.102 g for site class D.  The probability values at each grid point were then averaged to get a final grid of points representing the chance of potentially minor-damage ground shaking in 2018.  The data were imported into a grid and then contoured using ArcGIS.  The desired final contours were selected and polygon topology was ascertained as well as appropriate feature attributes.</procdesc><procdate>2018</procdate></procstep></lineage></dataqual><spdoinfo><direct>Vector</direct><ptvctinf><sdtsterm><sdtstype>G-polygon</sdtstype><ptvctcnt>23</ptvctcnt></sdtsterm></ptvctinf></spdoinfo><spref><horizsys><planar><mapproj><mapprojn>Albers Conical Equal Area</mapprojn><albers><stdparll>29.5</stdparll><stdparll>45.5</stdparll><longcm>-95.0</longcm><latprjo>0.0</latprjo><feast>0.0</feast><fnorth>0.0</fnorth></albers></mapproj><planci><plance>coordinate pair</plance><coordrep><absres>0.0001</absres><ordres>0.0001</ordres></coordrep><plandu>meters</plandu></planci></planar><geodetic><horizdn>D_Clarke_1866</horizdn><ellips>Clarke 1866</ellips><semiaxis>6378206.4</semiaxis><denflat>294.978698</denflat></geodetic></horizsys></spref><eainfo><detailed><enttyp><enttypl>WUS_ProbMMI6Shaking.shp</enttypl><enttypd>Areas of chance of potentially minor-damage shaking in 2018 that fall within a specified range</enttypd><enttypds>USGS</enttypds></enttyp><attr><attrlabl>FID</attrlabl><attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef><attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl><attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef><attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ValueRange</attrlabl><attrdef>The chance of potentially minor-damage shaking in 2018 within a polygon is within range of this value</attrdef><attrdefs>USGS</attrdefs><attrdomv><edom><edomv>&lt; 1</edomv><edomvd>Chance of potentially minor-damage shaking in 2018 is less than 1 percent within this polygon</edomvd><edomvds>USGS</edomvds></edom></attrdomv><attrdomv><edom><edomv>1-2</edomv><edomvd>Chance of potentially minor-damage shaking in 2018 within this polygon ranges between 1 and 2 percent</edomvd><edomvds>USGS</edomvds></edom></attrdomv><attrdomv><edom><edomv>2-5</edomv><edomvd>Chance of potentially minor-damage shaking in 2018 within this polygon ranges between 2 and 5 percent</edomvd><edomvds>USGS</edomvds></edom></attrdomv><attrdomv><edom><edomv>5-10</edomv><edomvd>Chance of potentially minor-damage shaking in 2018 within this polygon ranges between 5 and 10 percent</edomvd><edomvds>USGS</edomvds></edom></attrdomv><attrdomv><edom><edomv>10-14</edomv><edomvd>Chance of potentially minor-damage shaking in 2018 within this polygon ranges between 10 and 14 percent</edomvd><edomvds>USGS</edomvds></edom></attrdomv></attr></detailed></eainfo><distinfo><distrib><cntinfo><cntorgp><cntorg>U.S. Geological Survey - ScienceBase</cntorg></cntorgp><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing address</addrtype><address>Denver Federal Center, Building 810, Mail Stop 302</address><city>Lakewood</city><state>CO</state><postal>80215</postal><country>USA</country></cntaddr><cntvoice>1-888-275-8747</cntvoice><cntemail>sciencebase@usgs.gov</cntemail></cntinfo></distrib><resdesc>Downloadable geospatial data sets in shapefile format.</resdesc><distliab>Any use of trade, firm, or product names is for descriptive purposes only and does not imply endorsement by the U.S. Government. Although this information product, for the most part, is in the public domain, it also contains copyrighted materials as noted in the text. Permission to reproduce copyrighted items must be secured from the copyright owner whenever applicable. The data have been approved for release and publication by the U.S. Geological Survey (USGS). Although the data have been subjected to rigorous review and are substantially complete, the USGS reserves the right to revise the data pursuant to further analysis and review. Furthermore, the data are released on the condition that neither the USGS nor the U.S. Government may be held liable for any damages resulting from authorized or unauthorized use. Although the data have been processed successfully on a computer system at the U.S. Geological Survey, no warranty expressed or implied is made regarding the display or utility of the data on any other system, or for general or scientific purposes, nor shall the act of distribution constitute any such warranty. The U.S. Geological Survey shall not be held liable for improper or incorrect use of the data described and/or contained herein. Users of the data are advised to read all metadata and associated documentation thoroughly to understand appropriate use and data limitations.</distliab><stdorder><digform><digtinfo><formname>Shapefile</formname><formvern>10.3</formvern><formspec>ArcGIS version 10.3 shapefile format</formspec><formcont>Chance of potentially minor-damage shaking in 2018 based on the average of horizontal spectral response acceleration for 1.0-second period and peak ground acceleration</formcont><filedec>Files need to be decompressed using winzip or similar utility</filedec><transize>0.3</transize></digtinfo><digtopt><onlinopt><computer><networka><networkr>https://doi.org/10.5066/F7Cf9PC4</networkr></networka></computer></onlinopt></digtopt></digform><fees>none</fees></stdorder></distinfo><metainfo><metd>20180222</metd><metc><cntinfo><cntorgp><cntorg>U.S. Geological Survey - Geologic Hazards Science Center</cntorg><cntper>Ken Rukstales</cntper></cntorgp><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing address</addrtype><address>Box 25046, MS 966</address><city>Lakewood</city><state>CO</state><postal>80225</postal><country>USA</country></cntaddr><cntvoice>303-273-8677</cntvoice><cntemail>ghsc_metadata@usgs.gov</cntemail></cntinfo></metc><metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn><metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv><mettc>local time</mettc></metainfo></metadata>